Julian Voß

(+49) 541-969-4260 \diamond julian.voss@uni-osnabrueck.de Osnabrück University Chair of Comparative Politics Seminarstraße 33 \diamond 49074 Osnabrück

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My interests span a range of topics in Comparative Politics. I study the formation and change of political attitudes and behavior in the context of contention, autocratic politics, and regime change. In my research I mostly rely on causal inference designs using observational data as well as survey experiments. In my dissertation project I investigate the implementation and downstream consequences of personnel transitional justice policies.

EDUCATION

Doctoral Candidate, Political Science Osnabrück University	Since 2021
M.A., Political Science Osnabrück University	2021
B.A., Political Science and Economics Osnabrück University	2019
Professional Experience	
Research Fellow Comparative Politics Osnabrück University	Since 10/2021
Research Assistant V-Dem Institute University of Gothenburg	11/2020 - 01/2021
Research Assistant Comparative Politics Osnabrück University	03/2020 - 10/2021
Teaching Assistant Insitute of Social Science Osnabrück University	10/2019 - 02/2020

WORKING PAPER

Political purges and social ties: Evidence from denazification

Right-wing terror, public backlash, and voting preferences for the far right (with Alexander De Juan and Felix Haas)

Information about corruption and voting behavior: Evidence from a natural experiment in Germany

WORK IN PROGRESS

Transitional Justice and Support for Policies of Remembrance

Revisiting History, Reshaping Politics: The Effects of Confronting In-Group Atrocities (with Alexander De Juan, Sascha Riaz, and Anton Peez)

Does left-wing protest spark nationalist backlash? Evidence from Germany's 1968 student movement.

Presentations

American Political Science Association	2022, 2023
Network of European Peace Scientists	2022
PolMeth Europe	2023
Additional training	
Estimate Workshop Difference-in-Differences	2021 Michigan State University
Oxford Spring School Causal inference	2022 University of Oxford
Oxford Spring School Machine learning	2023 University of Oxford
TEACHING EXPERIENCE	
Introduction to Quantitative Conflict Studies MA-level	2022, 2023 Osnabrück
Introduction to Data Visualization MA- / BA-level	2022, 2023 Osnabrück
Regime Transitions in Europe	2022

Osnabrück

2021, 2022

Osnabrück

LANGUAGES

BA-level

BA-level

German (Native), English (Fluent), French (Basic), Russian (Basic)

SOFTWARE

R, STATA, Python, $\mbox{\sc IAT}_{\mbox{\sc E}}\mbox{\sc X}$

Techniques of Academic Work